科幻类
有什么我可以效劳的吗
Can I help you?
当然  德扬探员和萧探员
Sure hope so. agents Deyoung and Shaw.
就问几个问题
Just need to ask you a few questions.
最近几天楼里有什么怪事发生吗
Notice anything strange in the building,last couple of days?
比如说呢
Like what?
有住户反应电灯闪烁之类的事么
Well,some other tenants reported flickering lights.
没有  怎么了
I don't think so. why?
有奇怪的声音吗
What about noises?
像是老鼠在墙里跑来跑去那种
Any skittering in the walls? kind of like rats?
联邦探员也调查鼠害吗
And the FBI is investigating a rodent problem?
那有没有骤冷的情况吗
What about cold spots?
感到温度突然下降之类的
Feel any sudden drops in temperature?
我就知道
I knew it!
你们在玩LARP吧
You guys are larping, aren't you?
-你说什么  -你们是粉丝
- Excuse me? - you're fans.
-什么粉丝  -LARP是啥
- Fans of what? - What is "larping"?
别装了
Like you don't know.
真人角色扮演啊
Live-action role-playing.
看起来你们相当专业
And pretty hardcore,too.
抱歉  我不知道你在说什么
I'm sorry, I have no idea what you're talking about.
你们问的这些问题就好像这楼里闹鬼似的
You're asking questions like the building's haunted.
就像书里的角色一样
Like those guys from the books.
那书叫什么来着
What are they called?
《凶鬼恶灵》
"Supernatural."
两个男人  伪造身份  用不同的化名
Two guys,use fake i.d.s with rock aliases,
在全国各地狩猎鬼魂  恶魔和吸血鬼
Hunt down ghosts, demons,vampires.
他们叫什么来着
What are their names?
斯蒂文和德克
Steve and Dirk?
还是萨尔和戴恩
Sal and Dane?
-是萨姆和迪恩吗  -对
- Sam and Dean? - that's it!
你是说有写这些的这么一本书
You're saying this is a book?
不是一本  是一系列
Books. it was a series.
虽然卖得不怎么好
Didn't sell a lot of copies, though.
不过忠粉还是很有很多的
Kind of had more of an underground-cult following.
我找找看
Let's see.
就是这本
Yeah.
我想这是第一本
That's the first one, I think.
特价区
《凶鬼恶灵》  作者是卡文·爱德路德
"Supernatural" by Carver Edlund.
《凶鬼恶灵》
加州高速公路上一个穿白衣的
孤身女人诱惑花心男人再杀之...
这一恐怖是事件却是
萨姆和迪恩找到父亲的首要线索
在空寂的加州高速路上
"along a lonely california highway,
一个神秘的白衣女子诱惑男人  走向死亡
A mysterious woman in white lures men to their deaths."
给我
Give me that.
你这儿有的这套《凶鬼恶灵》  我们全要了
We're gonna need all the copies of "supernatural you got.
[邪恶力量 第4季第18集]
未知的结局
The Monster At The End Of This Book
这真是太诡异了
This is freakin' insane.
这作家怎么会知道这些事
How's this guy know all this stuff?
你问住我了
You got me.
书中的每一件事儿  注意了是每一件
Everything is in here -- I mean everything.
从那辆种族歧视的卡车(S01E13)  到我上床的细节
From the racist truck to -- to me having sex.
我简直就是赤裸裸地在这儿让别人参观
I'm full-frontal in here, dude.
我们怎么以前没听说过呢
How come we haven't heard of them before?
他们相当地低调
They're pretty obscure.
这书几乎算不上是上市发行
I mean, almost zero circulation.
从05年就开始发行了
Started in '05.
出版商出版了一些之后  就破产了
The publisher put out a couple dozen before going bankrupt.
最后一本是《邪恶无终止》(S03E16)
And, uh, the last one -- "no rest for the wicked"
结局就是你坠入了地狱
Ends with you going to hell.
我不得不重申
I reiterate
真是太诡异了
Freakin' insane.
噢  瞧瞧  还真的是有粉丝
Check it out. there's actually fans.
-人虽然不多  你看过了吗  -看了
- Not many,but still. did you read this? - yeah.
粉丝的意见还挺多
Although for fans, they sure do complain a lot.
听听这个
Listen to this
辛派提可说  恶魔的故事太老套了
Simpatico says "the demon story line is trite, cliched,
总得来说就是很无聊
And overall craptastic."
是的  去你的吧  辛派提可  这可是我们的生活
Yeah, well, screw you, Simpatico. we lived it.
是啊  接着往下看
Yeah. well,keep on reading.
还有更赞的
It gets better.
这还有《萨姆女版》和《迪恩女版》
There are "Sam girls" and "Dean girls" and
同人迷是啥东西
What's a "Slash Fan"?
就是
As in...
萨姆同迪恩(鞭挞小说, 描写同性恋者)
Sam-slash-Dean.
在一起
Together.
像情侣那样么
Like, together together?
是的
Yeah.
他们知道我们是兄弟吧
They do know we're brothers,right?
那根本无足挂齿
Doesn't seem to matter.
拜托  这
Come on. that...
也太变态了吧
That's just sick.
我们要把这个卡文·爱德路德找出来
We got to find this Carver Edlund.
-可能不容易  -为什么
- Yeah,that might not be so easy. - why not?
没有税务记录  没有地址
No tax records, no known address.
卡文·爱德路德应该是个笔名
Looks like "Carver Edlund" is a pen name.
肯定有人知道他的真实身份吧
Somebody's got to know who he is.
所以你就是《凶鬼恶灵》的出版商
So you published the "Supernatural" books?
是的  天哪  这些书
Yep. yeah. Gosh. these books...
它们居然得不到应有的重视
You know,they never really got the attention they deserved.
人们都只想看那些讲狗屁爱情的书
All anybody wants to read anymore is that romance crap.
像性感医生那种  真是够了
You know -- "doctor sexy,M.D."? Please.
是啊
Right.
我们就是希望我们的小说
Well,we're hoping that our article
能够重获重视  备受瞩目
Can shine a light on an underappreciated series.
没错  因为
Yeah,yeah, because,you know,
如果我们能好好地做下宣传
If we got a little bit of good press,
也许就能再次发行出版了
Then m-maybe we could start publishing again.
不  不  天哪  不要
No,no,no,no. god, no.
我只是想问你  为什么你会那么想出版他们
I mean,why -- why would you want to do that?
它不是已经完结了吗
You know, it's, uh, such a complete series,
迪恩不是已经坠入地狱了吗
What with Dean going to hell and all.
天哪  我最爱的就是这个情节了
Oh,my god! that was one of my favorite ones,
迪恩他是那么  坚强
Because dean was so... strong
那么忧伤和勇敢
And sad and brave.
萨姆也是
And Sam
最最大爱的就是他们落泪的那一刻
I mean,the best parts are when they'd cry.
比如《心之归属》(S02E17)里面写到的
You know, like in -- in "heart,"
当萨姆不得不杀掉麦迪逊那一刻
When Sam had to kill Madison,
她是杰西卡死后第一个他真正爱上的女人
The first woman since Jessica he really loved.
还有《回家》(S01E09)那一本  迪恩不得不给约翰打电话
And in "Home," when Dean had to call John
向他求助那一幕
And ask him for help.
天哪
Gosh
如果现实中有男人也能如此流露
If only real men were so open
表露他们的真实感情的话
And in -- in touch with their feelings.
现实中
Real men?
不要介意  我只是想说
I mean,no offense.
你几时有像那样伤心地痛哭过
How often do you cry like that,hmm?
现在  此刻我内心就正痛哭流涕着
Well,right now, I'm crying on the inside.
你觉得那很滑稽吗
Is that supposed to be funny?
美女  这根本就太扯了
Lady,this whole thing is funny.
我怎么知道你们是不是真有诚意呢
How do I know you two are legit,hmm?
请相信我
Trust me.
我们很有  诚意
We,uh... we're legit.
我可不想让某些自以为是的家伙
Well, I don't want any smart-ass article
糟蹋我家两小子
Making fun of my boys.
- 不  绝不会  -不会的 其实...
- No! no,no. never. - no,that's
我们...我们是
We--we are actually
超级粉丝
Big fans.
这么说你们也读过了
You've read the books?
从头至尾
Cover to cover.
那辆车的年代和型号
What's the year and model of the car?
1967年的雪佛兰黑羚羊
1967 Chevy Impala.
-5月2日是  -那是我的
- What's may 2nd? - that's my...
是萨姆的生日
That's Sam's birthday.
迪恩的生日是1月24日
January 24th is Dean's.
萨姆在法学院入学考试的分数是
Sam's score on the lsat?
一百
1...
七十四分
74?
-迪恩最喜欢的歌是  -真是很纠结啊
- Dean's favorite song? - It's a tie.
齐柏林飞艇的《漫谈》和
Between zep's "Ramble On"
《沿江蓝调》两首都爱
And "Traveling Riverside Blues."
很好  好吧
Okay. okay.
你们想知道什么
What do you want to know?
卡文·爱德路德的真名字
What's Carver Edlund's real name?
不行  抱歉  我不能说
Oh,no. no. sorry. I can't.
我们只想和他谈谈
We just want to talk to him.
就是想和他本人交流下《凶鬼恶灵》的那些事儿
You know,get the "supernatural" story in his own words.
他很避世的
He's very private.
就像J.D.塞林格一样
Like salinger.
拜托了
Please.
正如我所说  我们可是...
Like I said - we are...
超级
...big...
超级粉丝
...big fans.
太赞了
Awesome.
知道吗
You know what?
我也有一个
I got one,too.
你真是个狂热份子
You are a fan.
好吧
Okay.
他的名字叫恰克·舒尔利
His name's Chuck Shurley.
他可是个天才  所以别把他惹毛了
And he's a genius, so don't piss him off.
萨姆和迪恩走近破旧的
"Sam and Dean approached the run-down..."
怀揣着不安地走近那遥遥欲坠的房子
"Approached the ramshackle house with trepidation."
他们真得想要揭开那
"Did they really want to learn the secrets
禁闭房门背后的秘密吗
"That lay beyond that door?
萨姆和迪恩意味深长地交换了下眼神
Sam and Dean traded soulful looks."
便  下定了决心
"then, with determination,
迪恩摁下门铃  相当地
"Dean pushed the doorbell with forceful...
笃定
Determination."
是恰克·舒尔利吗
You Chuck Shurley?
写《凶鬼恶灵》的恰克·舒尔利吗
The Chuck Shurley who wrote the "Supernatural" books?
算是吧  怎么了
Maybe. why?
我是迪恩  这是萨姆
I'm Dean. this is Sam.
就是你笔下的迪恩和萨姆
The Dean and Sam you've been writing about.
听着
Look,uh...
我很感激你们的热情支持  真的  我很感谢
I appreciate your enthusiasm. really,I do.
有粉丝来拜访这真的太好了
It's, uh, it's always nice to hear from the fans.
但是  为了你们自己好
But, uh, for your own good,
我强烈建议你们做点别的有益的事
I strongly suggest you get a life.
问题是
See, here's the thing.
我们的生活
We have a life.
全都在你书中历历在目
You've been using it to write your books.
等一下  这可不一点也不好笑
Now, wait a minute. now, this isn't funny.
绝对是他妈的不是玩笑
Damn straight, it's not funny.
我们只想知道你是怎么做到的
Look,we just want to know how you're doing it.
我什么也没干过
I'm not doing anything.
-你是个猎鬼者吗  -什么
- Are you a hunter? - what?
不  我就只是个作家
No. I'm a writer.
那你怎么那么了解魔鬼
Then how do you know so much about demons
还有西藏灵魂印记(S01E17)和魔童(S03E02)
And Tulpas and Changelings?
是在模仿《战栗游戏》(斯蒂芬·金的小说)是不
Is this some kind of "Misery" thing?
没错吧  就是在模仿《战栗游戏》
It is, isn't it? it's a "Misery" thing!
跟《战栗游戏》可没关系  听清楚了  我们不是你粉丝
It's not a "misery" thing. believe me,we are not fans.
你们想要什么
Well,then, what do you want?!
我是萨姆  这是迪恩
I'm Sam. and that's Dean.
萨姆和迪恩是虚构的人物
Sam and Dean are fictional characters.
我创造了他们  他们不是真的
I made them up! they're not real!
这都是真枪吗
Are those real guns?
这是真的盐弹和真的假身份证
And this is real rock salt and these are real fake I.D.S.
我真是服了你们俩了
Well, I got to hand it to you guys.
你们绝对是我的头号粉丝
You really are my number-one fans.
太强悍了
That's awesome.
我  我想我屋里还有些海报
So, I-I think I've got some posters in the house.
-恰克  站住  -等一下
- Chuck,stop. - Please wait.
请不要伤害我
Please,don't hurt me.
你究竟知道多少
How much do you know?
天使的事你也知道吗
Do you know about the Angels?
还有莉莉丝打破封印的事
Or Lilith breaking the seals?
等等  你们怎么知道的
Wait a minute. how do you know about that?
应该是问  你怎么会知道
The question is, how do you?
因为是我写的
'cause I wrote it.
你还在写吗
You kept writing?
当然  不过出版商破产之后
Yeah,even after the publisher went bankrupt,
接下来的部分就没有出版
But those books never came out.
等一下
Okay,wait a minute.
这是在开玩笑  是吧
This is some kind of joke, right?
是  费尔叫你们来这么干的吧
Did that -- did Phil put you up to this?
很高兴见到你
Well,nice to meet you.
我是迪恩·温切斯特  这是我弟弟萨姆
I'm Dean winchester, and this is my brother, Sam.
我从没在书中提过姓氏
The last names were never in the books.
也没和任何人说过
I never told anybody about that.
甚至就没写下来过
I never even write it down.
你们还在这儿
Oh! oh,you're still there.
是的
Yup.
真不是我的幻觉
You're not a hallucination.
不是
Nope.
那么只有一个解释了
Well, there's only one explanation.
很明显我就是上帝
Obviously I'm a god.
你不是上帝
You're not a god.
不然要怎么解释
How else do you explain it?
我笔下的角色  居然成真了
I write things and then they come to life.
是吧  我绝对是上帝
Yeah, no, I'm definitely a god.
还是一个残酷  而善变的神
A cruel, cruel, capricious god.
让你们经历的那些
The things I put you through
肉体上的折磨
The physical beatings alone.
是啊  但我们还是完整无缺
Yeah,we're still in one piece.
我杀了你们的老爸
I killed your father.
还活焚了你们老妈
I burned your mother alive.
之后你又再次经历了
And then you had to go through
发生在杰西卡身上的同样的悲剧
The whole horrific deal again with Jessica.
恰克
Chuck...
这都是为了啥啊
All for what?
都是为了更富戏剧性
All for the sake of literary symmetry.
我玩弄了你们的命运  你们的情感
I toyed with your lives, your emotions,
为了娱乐大众
For...entertainment.
你并没有玩弄我们  恰克  好吗
You didn't toy with us, Chuck,okay?
更没有创造我们
You didn't create us.
你们真的躲过了那些虫子(S01E08)
Did you really have to live through the bugs?
是的
Yeah.
幽灵船(S03E06)也是真的咯
What about the ghost ship?
那也是真的
Yes,that too.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
制作恐惧是一回事
I mean, horror is one thing,
但是要被迫活在恐惧中
But to be forced to live bad writing...
如果我知道这会成真的话
If i would have known it was real,
我一定不会让你们经历那一切的
I would have done another pass.
恰克  你不是上帝
Chuck, you're not a god!
我们觉得你可能会通灵
We think you're probably just psychic.
不可能
No.
如果我能通灵的话  我还写作干嘛
If I were psychic, you think I'd be writing?
写作可痛苦着呢
Writing is hard.
但冥冥之中  你就像是在
It seems that somehow, you're just...
关注着我们的命运
Focused on our lives.
是啊  就像远距离偷窥一样
Yeah,like laser-focused.
你现在还在创作吗
Are you working on anything right now?
我靠
Holy crap.
怎么了
What?
最后一本书
The,uh,latest book.
有点怪异
It's,uh, it's kind of weird.
怎么个怪异法
"weird" how?
太像冯内古特的作品了
It's very Vonnegut.
是写《五号屠宰场》和《猫的摇篮》那个冯内古特吗
"slaughterhouse-five," or "cat's cradle", Vonnegut
-你居然知道  -怎么了
- What? - what?
应该是冯内古特笔下的《基尔戈·特劳特》才对
It's,uh, "kilgore trout," vonnegut.
我把自己写进了书里
I wrote myself into it.
写道  我在自己家中
I wrote myself, at my house...
和笔下创作出的人物面对面
Confronted by my characters.
我坐在自助洗衣店
I'm sitting in a laundromat,
读着  我坐在洗衣店
Reading about myself sitting in a laundromat,
读到我自己  我头都绕疼了
Reading about myself -- my head hurts.
那家伙一定有些事没告诉我们
There's got to be something this guy's not telling us.
萨姆把那一大捆脏衣服扔进洗衣机
"Sam tossed his gigantic darks into the machine.
开始怀疑起恰克
"He was starting to have doubts about Chuck,
是否把所有真相都说了出来
About whether he was telling the whole truth."
-别读了  -"别读了"  萨姆说道
- Stop it. - "'Stop it,' Sam said."
猜猜你下步要做什么
Guess what you do next.
萨姆转身背对着迪恩
"Sam turned his back on Dean.
他的脸色  阴沉而郁闷
His face, brooding and pensive."
我不明白他是怎么办到的
I mean,I don't know how he's doing it,
但他的确写中了
But this guy is doing it.
我看不到你的脸  但肯定是写对了
I can't see your face, but those are definitely
看你那阴沉而郁闷的香肩就知道
Your "brooding and pensive" shoulders.
你刚刚在心里骂我混蛋了
You just thought I was a dick.
他确实挺牛的
The guy's good.
你又写了一段
You wrote another chapter?
在你们出现之前  写这东西真是轻松多了
This was all so much easier before you were real.
我们抗得住  就直说吧
We can take it. just spit it out.
尤其是你肯定不想听
You especially are not gonna like this.
我更不喜欢地狱
I didn't like hell.
跟莉莉丝有关
It's Lilith.
她会来找萨姆
She's coming for Sam.
来杀他吗
Coming to kill him?
什么时候
When?
就今晚
Tonight.
她就这么现身吗  就在这儿
She's just gonna show up? here?
莉莉丝充满诱惑性地拍了拍床
"Lilith patted the bed seductively.
萨姆向自己的欲望屈服了
"Unable to deny his desire, Sam succumbed,
他们便陷入了恶魔的激情欲火之中
And they sank into the throes of fiery demonic passion."
你跟我开玩笑的  对吗
You're kidding me,right?
-你觉得这很好笑吗  -难道不是吗
- You think this is funny? - you don't?
拜托  老哥
I mean,come on. Dude
恶魔的激情欲火
"Fiery demonic passion"?
这还只是个初稿
It's just a first draft.
等会儿  莉莉丝不是个小女孩吗
Wait,wait,wait,wait. Lilith is a little girl.
不  这次她是一个
No,uh, this time she's a --
来自印第安纳州布卢明顿的漂亮的牙科医生
"Comely dental hygienist from Bloomington, Indiana."
真不错
Great. perfect.
接下来呢  在
So what happens after the...
那恶魔激情什么的  之后呢
"Fiery demonic" whatever?
我也不知道  还没任何征兆呢
I don't know. that hasn't come to me yet.
迪恩  没什么好担心的
Dean, look, there's nothing to worry about.
莉莉丝和我  还上床
Lilith and me? in bed?
你的通灵能力是怎么给你征兆的
How does this whole psychic thing of yours work?
你是问整个流程吗
You mean my process?
对  你的整个流程
Yes,your "process."
通常是由一阵头痛开始
Well,it usually starts with a headache.
非常剧烈的头痛
A really bad headache.
阿司匹林都不管用  所以
Aspirin is useless, so...
我才一直喝酒
I drink.
直到入睡
Until I fall asleep.
第一次时
The first time it happened,
我还以为那只是个疯狂的梦
I thought it was just a crazy dream.
就是梦到我们的第一次吗
The first time you dreamt about us?
画面不停地变换  一直变换着
It flowed. it just -- it kept flowing.
一直都这样  我根本无法控制
Still does. I-I can't stop it,really.
你不会真的相信
You can't seriously believe --
这不是玩笑
Humor me.
为什么我们不
Why don't we, we just...
先看看  再做决定之后的事呢
Take a look at these and see what's what.
你
You --
对  我知道你会要那些稿子
...knew you were gonna ask for that. yeah.
迪恩  行了
Dean,come on.
小货车的撞击虽不严重
"The minivan accident wasn't that bad,
但是迪恩还是有点儿眼冒金星
"But Dean was still seeing stars.
他茫然地抓下脸上那些带粉色小花的创口贴
"He scratched absently at the pink-flower band-aids on his face."
怎么了
So?
我见过你鲜血四溅
So, I've seen you gushing blood.
你宁可缠着胶带或破布条
You'd use duct tape and bar rags
也绝不会贴带粉色小花的创口贴
Before you'd put on a pink-flower band-aid.
-你到底想说啥  -我想说的是  这一切
- What's your point? my point is this -- all of this --
根本就不可能的 就是胡扯
I-is totally implausible. it's nuts.
迄今为止他写的所有事全都发生
He's been right about everything so far.
你觉得这会是一早就设计好了的吗
You think he's just gonna ground out at first now?
迪恩最钟爱的黑斑羚  后窗玻璃支离破碎
"Dean slid behind the wheel of his beloved Impala
迪恩气得绝尘而去
"And drove off,
而后窗上挂着的那块油布
"The plastic tarp on the rear window
飘动得犹如乌鸦的翅膀
Flapping like the wings of a crow."
一块油布
A tarp?
对  挂在车后窗  你就这样驶走了
Yeah. on the rear window. and you drive it like that.
或许在细节上他的预测不太精准
Well,he might be wrong about the details,
但结局却没出过什么错
But it doesn't mean he's wrong about the end result.
所以我们只好夹着尾巴开溜
So we're just gonna run?
我们现在根本就还不够格
We are a long way from ready
跟莉莉丝面对面地硬碰硬
For a face-to-face death match with Lilith.
停下
Hold on!
出什么问题了吗
What seems to be the problem?
大桥现在不能通过
Bridge is out ahead.
我们只想离开这个小镇
We're just trying to get out of town.
恐怕不行了
Yeah,afraid not.
-有其他路吗  -没有
- Is there a detour? - nope.
没有其他路通往高速公路了吗
There's not a side road that takes us to the highway?
要上高速  就得先过河
To get to the highway, you have to cross that river.
要过河  就得先过桥
To cross the river, you have to take that bridge.
-河有多深  -抱歉
- How deep's the river? - sorry.
恐怕你俩不得不再在镇上留宿一晚了
Afraid you boys are gonna have to spend the night in town.
嘿  我有个妙计
Hey,this could be a good thing.
如果这将引导我们碰上莉莉丝
I mean,if this is what puts us on the path to Lilith,
那我们就来个反其道而行之
Then all we got to do is get off the path.
啥意思
How do you mean?
这就像是本避免我们犯错的行为规范手册
It's a blueprint of what not to do.
也就是说  手册指导我们向左走
I mean,if the pages say that we go left --
-那我们就该向右走  -完全正确
- Then we go right. - Exactly.
只要反其道而行之  自然不会步入那个结局
We get off-book. we never make it to the end.
今儿干脆反过来走走
It's opposite day.
上面说我们会大吵一架  那么
It says that we,uh, we get into a fight, so
坚决和平共处
No fighting.
你也别做调查
No research for you...
那你也不能吃熏肉芝士汉堡
No bacon cheeseburger for you.
没问题
Yeah,no problem.
我点其他东西好了
I'll just order something else.
有什么推荐
Hi,uh, what's good?
如果你喜欢汉堡
Well,if you like burgers,
奥普拉的女朋友曾赞过
Oprah's girlfriend said
我们这儿的熏肉芝士汉堡是全国最美味的
We had the best bacon cheeseburgers in the country.
是吗
Really?
请给我来份鸡肉色拉
I'll just have the cobb salad,please.
那我要...素食豆腐汉堡
I'll have the... veggie tofu burger.
谢谢
Thanks.
这整件事太荒谬了
This whole thing's ridiculous.
莉莉丝也荒谬吗
Lilith is ridiculous?
但我会跟她乱搞的构想就很荒谬
The idea of me hooking up with her is.
的确
Right.
因为那种事绝不会发生
'cause something like that could never happen.
迪恩  这是我们第一次
Dean, for the first time,
获知莉莉丝即将到来
We have warning that Lilith is close.
所以呢
So?
所以
So...
我们已经占领了先机
We've got the jump on her.
只需要在知道她现身的时间  地点
If we know when she's coming, we know where --
这可是个千载难逢的良机
This is an opportunity.
你是
Are you --
你竟说出这么不计后果的话  真让我心凉
It frustrates me when you say such reckless things.
我也很心凉
Well,it frustrates me
你情愿逃避也不愿正面迎战
When you'd rather hide than fight.
你的鸡肉色拉
Cobb salad for you.
你的素食豆腐汉堡
And the tofu veggie burger for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这不是逃避  而是保存实力
It's not hiding. it's being smart.
这叫留着青山在
It's picking your battles.
我们根本就还没做好准备
And this is a battle that we are not ready to fight.
天哪
Oh,my god.
太美味了
This is delicious.
豆腐真是超美味
Tofu is amazing!
不好意思
I am so sorry.
我给你错拿成了熏肉芝士汉堡
I gave you the bacon cheeseburger by mistake.
斗牛士汽车旅馆
有空房
大佬  这儿可是按时收费的
Dude,this place charges by the hour.
知道  手册上说
Yeah,well, the book says
莉莉丝在一家叫红的汽车旅馆找到你
Lilith finds you at the red motel.
所以  妓女客栈
Hence,the,uh, hooker inn.
反过来走走  还记得吗
It's opposite day, remember?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
放一些防范莉莉丝的符咒袋
Couple of hex bags ought to Lilith-proof the room.
那我  是要整晚就都窝这儿吗
So,what? I'm supposed to just hole up here all night?
乖乖照做  知道了吗
That's exactly what you're gonna do,okay?
千万别调查
And no research.
我不介意你
I don't care what you do --
是想活动下你的魔力手指
Use the magic fingers
还是看付费的《色情之家》
Or watch "casa erotica" on pay-per-view.
大佬  别这样
Oh,dude,come on...
只是以防万一罢了
Just call it insurance.
那你准备干嘛
What are you gonna do?
书上说我一整天
Well,the pages say that I spend all day
都驾着黑羚羊兜风  所以
Riding around in the Impala. so
我现在就去好好安置她
I'm gonna go park her.
乖一点  好吗
Behave yourself, would you?
不想叫服务小姐
No homework.
就看看色情片
Watch some porn.
斗牛士
红
你想见我
You wanted to see me?
是的
Yeah.
感谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
没什么
Yeah,sure.
我想知道你知道多少
I was just wondering how much you know...
我的事
About me.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你有没有预见到我
Have you seen visions of me
在没有迪恩的那段期间的情况
When I'm not with Dean?
你是问我是否知道恶魔之血的事儿吗
You want to know if I know about the demon blood.
你没告诉迪恩吧
You didn't tell Dean.
我压根就没写过
I didn't even write it into the books.
怕让你显得很冷血
I was afraid it would make you look unsympathetic.
-冷血吗  -当然了  萨姆
- Unsympathetic? - yeah,come on,Sam.
那可是吸血呢
I mean,sucking blood?
你心知肚明那很邪恶
You got to know that's wrong.
我也很害怕
It scares the hell out of me.
我清楚那份邪恶在我体内
I mean, I feel it inside of me.
我  真希望自己能抑制对它的渴望
I...I wish to god I could stop.
但你又总是依赖于它
But you keep going back.
我还能怎样呢
What choice have I got?
如果那能帮我杀了莉莉丝  阻止天启降世的话
If it helps me kill Lilith and stop the apocalypse --
我一直以为那是迪恩的任务
I thought that was Dean's job.
天使们不也是这么说的  不是
That's what the angels say,right?
迪恩已不是
Dean's not...
如今的他已经不复从前了
...he's not Dean lately.
自他从地狱回来后
Ever since he got out of hell.
就需要我从旁帮他一把
He needs help.
所以你就担起了他的责任
So you got to carry the weight?
从小到大都是他在照顾我
Well, he's looked after me my whole life.
我就不能回报他吗
I can't return the favor?
当然可以
Yeah,sure you can.
我是说  如果真这么简单的话
I mean if that's what this is.
不然还会是怎样
What else would it be?
我说不上
I don't know.
也许恶魔之血确实让你变强大了
Maybe the demon blood makes you feel stronger?
让你更有驾驭之欲
More in control?
不可能
No.
不是这样的
That's not true.
抱歉  萨姆
I'm sorry, Sam.
我知道这是个沉重的负担
I know it's a terrible burden --
觉得一切都寄托在你身上
Feeling that it all rests on your shoulders.
是吗
Does it?
一切真都寄托在我身上吗
All rest on my shoulders?
故事的发展来看是这样的
That seems to be where the story's headed.
我强大到今晚就能阻止莉莉丝了吗
Am I strong enough to stop Lilith tonight?
我不知道
I don't know.
我还看不到那么远
I haven't seen that far yet.
太好了  别紧张  你会没事的
Oh, god. just be take easy. you'll be OKay.
-星星  -你说什么
- Stars. - what was that?
真抱歉  刚才没看见你  你还好吗
I'm so sorry. I just didn't see you. are you okay?
还有  对不起
And sorry about...
你该了解
You know.
我女儿喜欢假扮医生
M-my daughter's going through a doctor phase.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你现在好多啦
You're better now.
不是吧
Oh,no...
迪恩
Dean.
我猜你早知道我会来吧
I take it you knew I'd be here.
你看起来很糟
You look terrible.
因为我被辆卡车给撞了  恰克
That's 'cause I just got hit by a minivan, Chuck.
就这样吗
That it?
每件你写的有关我的事都成真了
Every damn thing you write about me comes true.
你只 "噢"一句就完了
And all you have to say is "oh"?
别对我吼
Please don't yell at me.
为什么我总觉得
Why do I get feeling
你有事瞒着我们呢
There's something that you're not telling us?
我有什么好瞒的
What wouldn't I be telling you?
你怎么知道那些的  从头说起
How you know what you know, for starters!
我也不知道原因  就是知道
I don't know how I know. I just do.
这答案我不太满意
That's not good enough.
你他妈是怎么做到的
How the hell are you doing this?!
迪恩  放开他
Dean, let him go.
他是受庇护之士
This man is to be protected.
出于什么
Why?
他是上帝的先知
He's a prophet of the lord.
你
You...
你是卡西迪奥
You're castiel...
对不
Aren't you?
很荣幸见到你  恰克
It's an honor to meet you, Chuck.
我很钦佩你的成果
I admire your work
什么啊  这家伙  是个先知
Whoa,whoa,what? this guy,a prophet?
拜托  他  他...
Come on,he's -- he's...
他根本就是个顾影弄姿小作家罢了
He's practically a penthouse forum writer!
你早就知道自己是先知对不
Did you know about this?
我  貌似确实有梦到过吧
I,uh, I might have dreamt about it.
那你却不告诉我们
And you didn't tell us?!
这也太荒谬了
It was too preposterous.
更别说还很自负
Not to mention arrogant.
把自己写进书里就算了
I mean,writing yourself into the story is one thing,
还写成个先知
But as a prophet?
那根本就是夜郎自大的表现嘛
That's like m. night-level douchiness.
这就是决定我们命运的人吗
This is the guy who decides our fate?
他啥也决定不了
He isn't deciding anything.
他只是个代言人
He's a mouthpiece --
只是道出圣言的人罢了
A conduit for the inspired word.
圣言
The word?
上帝的圣言吗
The word of god?
别跟我说这是一本全新的新约圣经
What, like the new new testament?
总有一天  这些书
One day,these books --
会被称为温彻斯特福音而广为流传的
They'll be known as the winchester gospel.
-你开玩笑的吧  -你开玩笑的吧
- You got to be kidding me. - you got to be kidding me.
我没有...  开玩笑
I am not... kidding you.
可以的话  我先闪人了
If you'd both please excuse me one minute.
就他  真的假的
Him? really?
你要是见过路加的话
You should've seen Luke.
为什么会选他
Why'd he get tapped?
我不知道先知都是怎么选出来的
I don't know how prophets are chosen.
那是由高等级天使下令挑选的
The order comes from high up on the celestial ch command
-多高的  -非常高
- How high? - very.
随便吧  那我们怎么解决这事
Well,whatever. how do we get around this?
解决什么
Around what?
萨姆-莉莉丝的爱之深接触
The Sam-Lilith love connection.
要怎样阻止来着
How do we stop it from happening?
先知所写的绝非儿戏
What the prophet has written can't be unwritten.
既然他已经看到了  就一定会发生
As he has seen it, so it shall come to pass.
红
走吧  我们离开这儿
Come on. we're getting out of here.
什么  去哪
What? where?
哪里都行
Anywhere,okay?
离开这个旅馆  离开这个镇子
Out of this motel, out of this town.
又算是用游的  我们也要游走
I don't care if we got to swim, we are getting out.
老弟  那些该死的符咒包呢
Dude,where are all the hex bags?
被我烧了
I burned them.
你干了啥
You what?
听着  如果莉莉丝真会来  不管这可能性有多大
Look,if Lilith is coming, which is a big "if"
不  不  不  莉莉丝是真的要来
No,no,no. it's more than an "if."
恰克不是什么通灵者
Chuck is not a psychic.
-而是个先知  -啥
- He's a prophet. - what?
卡西迪奥现身
Cass showed up,
并告诉我说  恰克所写的正是你我的福音录
And apparently chuck is writing the gospel of us.
收到
Okay.
那好  我们立马走人
Okay. let's get the hell out of here.
我不走
No.
莉莉丝会宰了你的
Lilith is gonna slaughter you.
说不定她不会  或是根本办不到
Maybe she will, maybe she won't.
所以呢  你觉得自己能反过来宰了她
So what? you think you can take her?
要知道答案的唯一方法  迪恩
Only one way to find out, Dean,
就是让她放马过来
And I say bring her on.
-萨姆  -你不相信我  是吗
- Sam... - you think I'll do it, don't you?
你觉得我会选择堕落
You think I'll go dark side.
是的  行了吧
Yes! okay? yes.
瞧瞧你最近的所作所为
The way you've been acting lately?
你干得那些事情
The things you've been doing?
是的  我都知道了
Oh, I know.
比如你杀阿拉斯泰尔时  如何得不费吹灰之力
How you ripped Alastair apart like it was nothing,
就像拍死了一只苍蝇
Like you were swatting a fly.
卡西都跟我说的  行了吧
Cass told me, okay?
他还跟你说了些什么
What else did he tell you?
都是我不知道的事情
Nothing I don't already know.
比如你正在使用自己的能力
That you've been using your psychic crap,
而且你也变得越来越强了
And you've been getting stronger.
我们只是不清楚何以这样  也不知你如何办到的
We just don't know why, and we don't know how.
并不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
那你说说看啊  萨姆
Then what is it, Sam?
我现在是一头雾水
'cause I'm at a total loss.
要不要跟我一起走
Are you coming or not?
不
No.
好吧  虽然我觉得这么做很傻  但
Well, I feel stupid doing this. but
我别无选择
I am fresh out of options.
所以  拜托
So,please...
请帮帮我
I need some help.
我在祈祷  听到了吗
I'm praying, okay?
现身吧
Come on.
求你了
Please.
祈祷是信仰的一种表现
Prayer is a sign of faith.
这是件好事  迪恩
This is a good thing, Dean.
那么你是愿意帮我了吗
So does that mean you'll help me?
我不知道该怎么帮你
I'm not sure what I can do.
马上带萨姆离开
Drag Sam out of here -- now.
在莉莉丝现身前
Before Lilith shows up.
这可是个预言
It's a prophecy.
我无能为力
I can't interfere.
你用尽各种方法不断考验我
You have tested me and thrown me every which way.
而我从没要求什么
And I have never asked for anything.
一次都没
Not a damn thing.
但现在我请求你
But now I'm asking.
帮帮我
I need your help.
求你了
Please.
你的请求  它
What you're asking,it's...
超出了我的能力
Not within my power to do.
-为什么  就因为那是上帝的预言  -是的
- Why? 'cause it's "divine prophecy"? - Yes.
难道我们就该坐以待毙
So,what -- we're just supposed to sit around
仍其发展吗
A-and wait for it to happen?
对不起
I'm sorry.
见你的鬼去吧
Screw you.
你以及你那鬼任务
You and your mission.
还有你那上帝
Your god.
如果你现在不帮我
If you don't help me now,
下次你需要我的时候
Then when the time comes and you need me...
就别再来找我了
...don't bother knocking.
迪恩
Dean.
Dean!
干嘛
What?!
你得了解清楚为什么我不能插手
You must understand why I can't intercede.
先知们非常特别  他们受神庇护
Prophets are very special. they're protected.
我早就知道了
I get that.
如果有任何威胁  无论是什么
If anything threatens a prophet, anything at all,
大天使都会现身  将其铲除
An archangel will appear to destroy that threat.
大天使们都异常的暴戾
Archangels are fierce.
而且六亲不认
They're absolute.
他们是天堂里最可怕的武器
They're heaven's most terrifying weapon.
而正是这些大天使  保护着先知
And these archangels, they're tied to prophets?
是的
Yes.
如果先知和恶魔共处一室的话
So if a prophet was in the Same room as a demon --
那么可怕的天堂之怒
Then the most fearsome wrath of heaven
会降临到恶魔身上
Would rain down on that demon.
我只想让你明白  为什么我帮不了你
Just so you understand... why I can't help.
谢谢  卡西
Thanks, cass.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你在这儿干嘛呢  我没写过这一出啊
What are you doing here? I didn't write this.
快
Come on.
我要你跟我一起走
I need you to come with me.
-什么  去哪  -去萨姆在的那个汽车旅馆
- What? where? - to the motel where Sam is.
莉莉丝也在那儿
That's where Lilith is.
是的  没错  我就是找你帮忙阻止她的
Yeah, exactly. I need you to stop her.
你疯了吗  那可是莉莉丝啊
Are you insane? Lilith?
迪恩  我清楚她的能力  我写过她的
I know what she's capable of, Dean -- I wrote her.
行了  你听着
All right, listen to me.
你有一个大天使守护着  明白吗
You have an archangel tethered to you,okay?
你只需到那儿露个脸  让大天使爆发一下
All you got to do is show up and boom!
莉莉丝就玩儿完了
Lilith gets smoked.
但是  我  我从没预见那一出啊
But I-I-I haven't seen that yet.
那个故事
T-the story --
恰克  你可是我的救命稻草呢
Chuck, you're the only shot that I've got left.
但
But...
我只是一个作家
I'm just a writer.
但这已经不再是个故事了  老兄
This isn't a story anymore,man.
已经木已成舟  你也逃脱不了干系了
This is real! and you're in it!
现在  我希望你能奋力一搏
Now, I need you to get off your ass and fight.
来吧  恰克
Come on,chuck.
没门
No friggin' way.
好吧  那么  要不这样
Okay,well,then, how about this --
我口袋里正躺着一把枪
I've got a gun in my pocket,
你不跟我走  我就爆了你的头
And if you don't come with me, I'll blow your brains out.
我记得你说过有大天使守护着我
I thought you said I was protected by an archangel.
这个理由不错嘛
Well, interesting exercise.
那就看看谁更快
Let's see who the quicker draw is.
勿扰
你好啊  萨姆
Hello, Sam.
等你很久了
I've been waiting for you.
萨姆 刀在哪
where is the knife, Sam?
就在床头柜那
On the nightstand. by the bed.
你就只有这点儿小伎俩了
You're gonna have to try a lot harder than that.
尝尝这个怎样
How 'bout this?
你变强大
You're strong.
不过还不够强
But you're not that strong.
差得还远呢
Not yet.
那你干嘛不把我扔走
So why don't you throw me around then?
因为我办不到  你心知肚明
Because I can't and you know it.
你早对我的魔力免疫了
You're immune to my charms.
看来我们势均力敌啊
Seems we're at a stalemate.
你来干嘛
Why are you here?
聊聊
To talk.
好吧  我没兴趣
Yeah,well, I'm not interested.
即使我自愿从封印之战中
Even if i'm offering to stand down...
退出
From the seals...
天启
The apocalypse...
所有的一切
All of it?
你还期待我会相信你吗
You expect me to believe that?
说真的  没想过
Honestly? no.
你可没那么好唬弄
You were always the smart one.
但这次是真的
But it's the truth.
你可以终止这一切  萨姆
You can end it,Sam.
就此时  此地
Right here,right now.
我会停止打破封印
I'll stop breaking seals,
让路西法在笼子里腐烂
Lucifer keeps rotting in his cage.
只要你答应我的条件
All you have to do is agree to my terms.
为什么要放弃
Why would you back down?
为什么偏挑这个时候
Why now?
最后的结果是  我无法在这场战争中幸免
Turns out, I don't survive this war.
要终结  就应该从源头下手
Killed off, right before the good part starts.
你究竟想要什么
What do you want?
为了能重回旧秩序
For it to go back to the way it was.
在我被天使们夺命索魂前
Before I had angels to deal with 24/7.
那美好的往日
The good old days,
每天都沐浴在婴儿的鲜血之中
When it was all baby blood all the time.
那代价呢
And what do you want in return?
你的项上人头
Your head on a stick.
还有迪恩的
Dean's,too.
就当是个安慰奖
Call it a consolation prize.
怎么样  萨姆
So what do you say, Sam?
温彻斯特家族不是最爱自我牺牲的  不是吗
Self-sacrifice is the winchester way, isn't it?
你还真的以为我会蠢到相信你的鬼话吗
You really think I'm stupid enough to fall for this?
我跟你交易了  我就必须得遵守
I make a deal, I have to follow through.
这就是规矩啊  你清楚得很
Those are the rules, and you know it.
难道你真妄自尊大到
Are you really so arrogant
把自己的命
That you would put your life
看得比60亿无辜的人的命还重要吗
Before the lives of 6 billion innocent people?
也许是你体内的恶魔之血在作祟
Maybe it's all that demon blood pumping through your pipes.
这一点真是合我的心意
Man after my own heart.
你以为我跟你志趣相投
You think I'm like you?
我跟你没有任何共同点
I am nothing like you.
那就证明给我看啊
Then prove it.
有第一次
Going once.
总会有第二次
Going twice.
好  成交
Fine.
了不起
Swell.
顺便说一下  跟我做交易不单单只是个吻
By the way,a contract with me will take more than a kiss.
要做得更多
A lot more.
别担心
Don't worry.
我附身的这位牙医小姐
The dental hygienist in here?
她想这事都想疯了
She wants it bad.
我是先知恰克
I am the prophet Chuck!
开什么玩笑
You've got to be joking.
这不是在开玩笑
This is no joke.
看吧  恰克有大天使的守护
See, Chuck here's got an archangel on his shoulder.
你有10秒钟可逃
You've got about 10 seconds
在这间屋子充满了天堂之怒
Before this room is full of wrath
把你震成灰烬之前
And you're a piece of charcoal.
你真想继续纠缠下去吗
You sure you want to tangle with that?
又是交易
so a deal,ha
她是这么说的
That's what she said.
为了要终结一切
To call the whole thing off --
天使  封印  路西法的复出  所有的一切
Angels, Seals, Lucifer rising, the whole nine?
大概就这样
That was the gist of it.
怎么啦
What?
你就没心动一下吗
You didn't think once about taking it?
开什么玩笑
You kidding me?
你花了一整天来说服我远离莉莉丝
You spent all day trying to talk me off the Lilith track.
我只是想提醒下你
I'm just saying...
她可能真找到什么方法终结这一切
She would have found some way to weasel out of it.
也许就是要我们作出牺牲就行了
And all it would have cost us was our lives.
对啊  也许你说得没错
Yeah, I guess you're right.
但无论如何  这都不是重点
Anyway. that's not the point.
那重点是什么
What's the point?
重点是  她在害怕
The point is, she's scared.
我看得出来
I could see it.
莉莉丝在逃跑
Lilith is running.
-为什么要逃跑  -不知道
- Running from what? - don't know.
可是她透露了一个事实
But she was telling the truth about one thing.
什么
What's that?
天启降世她也无法幸存
She's not gonna survive the apocalypse.
我会弄个水落石出的
I'll make sure of that.
你看到了吗
Did you see it?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是撒迦利亚
I'm zachariah.
从你的作品里应该认识我了吧
You may know me from your work.
你想怎样
What do you want?
你看到了
Did you see it?
是真的吗
Is it true?
那一切  真的会发生吗
Is all of that... really going to happen?
你以前有错过吗
Have you been wrong so far?
我得马上去警告萨姆和迪恩
I got to warn Sam and Dean.
我建议你别去
I wouldn't advise it.
有时候对自己命运不用知之甚详
People shouldn't know too much about their own destiny.
你可以试试看
You try...
我会阻止你的
And I'll stop you.
你要去干嘛
Where are you going?
自杀
To go kill myself.
别那么琼瑶嘛  恰克
Don't be Melodramatic, Chuck.
我们只会再把你救活的
We'd only bring you back to life.
那我该怎么做
What am I supposed to do?
一如既往
What you always do.
写下来
Write.